Pretty much everyone can get, um, better
bang for your buck by using a lower
effort level. Lower effort basically
means fewer tokens spent on exploration.
So, the agent is more efficient as it
goes through your code base. Exploration
is a task that you don't really need
effort for. As you crank up the effort,
the agent is going to be spending more
thinking tokens to do the same work,
more reasoning tokens. And what that
means is that it's going to push harder
on things that you don't need to push
on. Everyone looks at the charts for the
benchmarks that models use and they see
that, okay, if you crank it up to max
effort, you're going to get higher
quality outputs. The weird thing about
those charts is that they don't really
take into account the crucial thing,
which is that the tasks stay static,
whereas you have the opportunity as the
developer to change the way that you
specify tasks to make things easier for
the agent. The more high-quality
information you give it, the lower
effort you actually need to complete the
task. So, I recommend actually starting,
if you're using Opus or Fable or
something, starting with the lowest
effort you have access to and then
cranking it up from there. You do still
need a little bit of thinking tokens
just because chain of thought is such a
useful way of working with agents and
getting it to do good stuff, but
honestly, just try a lower effort level.
You'll be surprised by what you get.